Damn!The chicken is gone!
Get her,mister!
If the picture is good
I will work in a newspaper.
You are playing with your life
for a photograph?
Do you think that i am in the mood
to see the fucking gang?
The chicken bro!
The chicken i told you,asshole!
Get the chicken!
If Ze gets you,
you're dead.
He has to find me first.
Hey,kid!Get the chicken!
-The cops!
-Don't run!
Butthead! Motherfucker!
A photo might
have changed my life. . .
but in the City of God,
if you run you're dead. . .
...if you stay,
you're dead again.
It has always been like that
since i was a kid.
IN THE 60's
-You are so useless.
-Fetch the ball.
Hey, kid! Fetch the ball .
You are not giving it to me?
Fuck you.
What's your name?
Sorry,I forgot to introduce myself.
My name is Rocket.
Do not give the ball
to the kid, he stinks.
This is Hairy.
The story of the City of God
starts with him.
However, Hairy's story
is connected to Mortes Trio story.
The truck is coming.
Why are you fooling around?
TRIO MORTES STORY
Trio Mortes
the legend of the City of God!
Hairy.
Snatcher.
And Naive.
With them, Kid and
Benny, Hairy's brother.
I did not have enough courage
to go with my brother.
Come Naive!
Let's go!
Stop or I'll shoot,
fucking asshole.
Get out!
Quickly, asshole.
Give me the money!
Who wants gas?
Oh! You wanna die for money
that is not yours?
Lots of money here!
Damn! The cops!
Quickly!
They are everywhere!
Then, I thought that
Trio Mortes. . .
was the toughest gang
in Rio.
But they were just amateurs.
Even my bro
Naive.
Give these to dad
but do not tell him it's from me.
Hairy, come and see what I've got!
We came to the City of God
to find paradise.
Lot of people were homeless
due to the floods...
and the fire
they set in the ghetto.
They are going to bring electricity!
The big bosses however
didn't like the homeless.
Without electricity,without
roads,without buses.
The rich people...
They don't give a damn about us
It has nothing to do
with the Rio De Janeiro you see in postcards.
Do you think I am going to be
a lifeguard when I grow up?
I don't know.
It is better to be a
lifeguard than a fisherman.
I don't want to be a fisherman,
I will stink.
-Are you insulting your father?
-No.
-What do you want to become?
I sure don't want to be a gangster
or a cop.
I do not want to get killed.
Drop it, kid.
Are you pointing a gun at me?
The kid is with me.
I am a gangster too.
-Not many bottles in it.
-We rob trucks every day.
We have to hit a rich
house to get out of here.
No, you have to
follow my plan.
Look who's talking!
He is so stoned, he
doesn't know what he is talking about!
You are both not as
worthy as the kid.
What are you thinking, kid?
The gun doesn't make you a robber.
You need ideas.
The kid had ideas.
Is this the Motel?
We get the money and leave.
No killings!
-Give it to me.
-Leave me alone!
Don't you give this
shit to me!
You're acting like a baby.
-Here's yours.
-Awesome!
Do not be hasty. You're staying here
to look out.
If you see cops,
shoot that window.
Why doesn't he stay in the look-out?
This was my plan.
He is good for nothing!
Ok, you had the idea.
But you're just a kid!
Cover us.
Your turn is going to come.
Don't be so hasty.
Stay here.
This is a hold up, bitch.
You should be at school
or at work.
You do not look like robbers.
Shut up, bitch!
Ok, Snatcher?
Are we going in?
-I did not order anything.
-It's on the house! Your money!
Take it easy. All I want is your money.
Hey, pal!
What is this mess?
Are you a church boy?
Give it to me!
You are old, and ugly.
Do you want to fuck her?
Police! Let's beat it!
Take the car.
I'm gonna bring the kid.
-It went wrong. The kid is missing!
-They are shooting, let's go!
-You said you could drive.
-I can, cool down.
Turn! Watch it!
-You asshole!
-I didn't do it on purpose.
No one saw a thing.
Don't say a word, ok?
I twisted my leg!
-Naive is hit!
-It hurts!
Take him to the woods.
I will try to distract the cops.
God help us.
Get the phone.
Shortie. Infamous in the City.
I will talk about him later.
It hurts, God dammit!
Shut up!
You're acting like a sissy.
Give me your hand!
A whole car runs
into a bar...
and no one saw a thing?
As always. No one sees,
no one knows a thing.
-What's up, Shortie?
-They are hiding in the woods.
I think they
are hiding in the woods.
They are in the woods.
Fillipe, lock the car.
Rantzel, come with me.
Pitch black.
How do they see?
They stole a fortune
from the motel...
-What if we took the money?
-Are you out of your mind?
I do not want any trouble.
I just want to eliminate them.
Since when is it a crime
to steal from niggers and robbers?
I know a snitch in the City.
Did you hear the shootings?
If I find one of them, I will shoot him!
Maracana!
Open the door!
They are after me!
The police is after me!
Hide me!
Come inside.
Shit, the cops are
still down there.
-I had a vision, Naive.
-Did you smoke anything?
You had a job, right?
How is it? What do they say to you?
I worked for my father.
Fathers say bullshit.
I'm leaving. I do not want to die.
I am not meant to be a gangster.
-The cops are down there.
-I don't care.
I am going back to the church.
"I am the resurrection
and the life..
He that believeth in me,
though he were dead, yet shall he live..
And whosoever liveth
and believeth in me..
shall never die..."
Stop, or I'll shoot!
"He that believeth in me,
though he were dead, yet shall he live.."
The robbery in the motel
was the most bloodstained in history.
The gangsters fortunes
changed paths.
He must not have
been a gangster.
He is a worker.
Snatcher was
in God's hands.
Hairy was caught
in the net of Bernice.
and Naive was
in my father's hands.
Why are you doing this?
You will be working with me!
Your brother is
going to look after you.
If i ever catch you with money
that is not yours, I'll kill you!
This goes for you too.
Put on the work wear!
If your brother is a gangster
you are affected as well!
Don't worry.
He will get over it.
These things are not for you!
You go and study.
Aren't you afraid of being killed?
You are smart.
You have to go to college.
I attend school because
I do not like working.
Promise me that you are
never going to touch this weapon.
Quickly. I will sell
lots of fish. Do not laugh!
You smiled when father
hit me.
What's wrong?
Cat got your tongue?
I'm thinking how to tell you.
You're gonna fry your brain
if you think so much.
My heart chooses you.
I am listening to my heart.
Are you kidding?
Have you never heard
of love at first sight?
-Gangsters do not love.
-You always talk to me in a bad way.
-Gangsters seduce.
-I am not going to lose my peace.
Gangsters do not stop,
just take a break.
-You know nothing of love.
-This is no love, it is a joke.
I love you.
You might convince me
in the end.
After the robbery, police
carried out raids in the ghetto.
Everyday, someone was sent to jail,
someone was sold out.
But no one ever knew anything.
No one revealed the
robbers' hideout.
THREE MONTHS LATER
Why don't you change
life, Hairy?
Find a job instead of
lying in bed all day!
Do you think that a job will
give you money? Go try!
What do you think
I am doing all day long?
Take it easy, baby.
All I want is you.
To have children, a farm
with chickens, and lots of weed.
I do not believe a word.
I almost got rich
with that robbery.
The police are after you
after the motel killings.
What are you saying? Did you see anything?
So, shut up!
They shot them,
and blamed it on me!
They even killed the
Kid! So leave it!
-I don't know who did it
-Not me.
I do not want a gangster as
the father of my children!
You are alone, Hairy!
Snatcher became religious,
Naive found a job.
-And you?
-I am the same!
-Everybody dumped me.
-Then I will dump you too.
I am leaving. If you want, come with
me, or else i will leave alone!
Nice fresh fish!!
My brother promised
to conform.
But the gangster does not change.
Just stops for a while.
Naive was having an affair
with Shortie's wife.
I have trout, but for you
I have something special.
It's a mullet.
Does your husband lick you?
Mine, before fucking
he licks me for half an hour.
-From behind? Do you let him?
-No! Doesn't it hurt?
In the beginning,yes. After that, it
is perfect! But you need a banana.
-Why?
-You're losing the best part kid!
You warm up a banana
and stick it in your pussy!
while he fucks you in the ass.
It is awesome!
-Ask your husband.
-I can't. He will get mad
Try. Men go nuts
for stuff like that.
Fucking nigger!
Bitch!
Whore!
Rocket, give me your
shorts. Quickly!
-I am not gonna get naked in the street.
-Your brother is in danger!
Give me the shirt!
Quickly!
I always pay the price.
He ran away.
It's his brother.
I will cut his balls!
Fish! Fresh fish!
Kid, come here.
-Where is your brother?
-Not working today.
-Get in.
-I did nothing.
-What about my fish
-Get in. Forget the fish.
My father will
kill me.
Let's go. There is nothing here.
My father sweared not
to see my brother again.
No one saw him again
in the ghetto.
The Trio Mortes story
reaches its end.
Kid! I though you were killed
in the motel.
-I can see you got money.
-It's ours, Benny.
Cut the crap
and bring the money.
Tell Hairy that
Shortie is getting hard. I'm leaving
But, Shortie was busy
A neighbour called the cops
before sunrise.
The newpapers wrote:
''A husband burries his wife
alive in the City of God''
The place was full of cops.
The robbers ran away.
-Do you want to die?
-Do as I tell you.
Some respect to the lady.
-Let's go.
-There are cops ahead.
Fuck them, go away.
Go wherever you want.
What is up?
Mercy. It is a piece of crap.
-Start the engine!
-Needs pushing.
Push, Hairy.
Push!
You?
Do you want to arrest
the thieves? There...
Get him!
Run, Hairy!
Stop!
He's a murderer!
The day that Hairy
was killed...
I remember the crowd
and a camera.
I had always wanted a camera.
Let's go to school.
-Why don't we go to the beach?
-We have exams!
So what!
Everybody is at the beach!
She wears bikini
and plays hard to get!
Sun is for everyone.
Beach for a few.
IN THE 70's
When I was 16, I bought
my first camera.
Starting from the low.
The cheapest model!
How is it going, Rocket?
Have you been laid yet?
Nothing.
Angelica. She drove me mad...
Rocket, are you jerking?
Gorgeus and got laid.
I wanted to lose my virginity with her!
-She has a boyfriend.
-So? I am not jealous
-Her father is a cop.
-No one is perfect.
I was the official photographer
of the gang.
of the "Groovie Gang".
Everybody paid for copies.
Siago, move backwards.
There.
I need a joint.
Sniff coke.
It is great!
Siago do you sniff?
I prefer good pot.
-I can find some for you if you want.
-Go find then.
If we talk about dope,
we talk about coke!
Drugs!
-You're full of salt.
-Fuck off.
You want to be a lifeguard
but you never go in.
I bet a beer I
am a better swimmer.
If you want, I can find a joint
at Blackies.
I would do anything for her.
I would find pot, coke...
I would go to the big ones
to buy good stuff..
The boss was an ex
classmate: Blackie.
-Who?
-Rocket!
Who are things going?
The kids ok?
Do you want to buy
or smoke?
Who is it?
This was Blackies hideout.
But not always.
Fuck off Kid.
Why are you marching in like that?
Is this your hideout?
THE STORY OF THE HIDEOUT
Dona Zel after becoming a widow
she started to sell drugs...
to feed her children.
She often gave out dope to the
kids in exchange for special favors.
Her favourite was
the Big Guy.
She was such an amateur
that even Big Guy was cheating on her.
Big Guy was using kids
as dealers.
-My pot?
-Stick it in your ass.
The best dealer...
was Redhead.
May I have a sip?
Big Guy trusted him
and so he became a manager.
Twenty for us.
Five for you, Blackie.
One day a friend of Redhead's appeared.
Aristotle.
My wife is sick.
His family had helped
Redhead.
He would not refuse help
to a brother.
The dope. I want the money
on Friday.
You got me out of jail.
He is a friend, Big Guy.
Give him another week.
You either kill him or I'll kill you.
He had no choice.
-I told you on Friday.
-Do not do it friend.
Redhead wanted to get
the Big Guy...
But he did not have to.
Big Guy died in jail.
Redhead took the
belongings of Big Guy...
But not the hideout.
It was cursed.
He gave it to his trustee
Blackie.
-One Hundred fifty bags.
-Not enough.
So he took over
the local dealing.
But not for long.
Who is it?
Go see.
Fuck off Kid. Why are
you rushing into my hideout?
Who told you
it is yours?
And I am not Kid.
My name is Ze.
THE STORY OF LITTLE ZE
Ze wanted to rule
the City of God...
since he was a kid.
They are having fun and I am not?
I want to go.
What do you want?
Your friend took it all.
That night, Kid
satisfied his thirst for blood,
knowing that Hairy
would never forgive him.
To save himself,
he left the City of God.
He worked all day for nickels.
Kid and Benny
really made it...
They had the gift of the killer.
-You have more.
-I had the idea.
The problem was to handle
an older gangster.
Like my brother Goose.
Dammit! I though you died in the motel.
You have lots of money!
It is our money, Benny.
Benny, tell Hairy that
Shortie is getting difficult.
I'm leaving the ghetto.
From Hairy.
You are gonna need it.
Robbery after robbery,
the Kid grew big.
By the time he was 18, he was the
most respected gangster in the City
One of the most
dangerous robbers in Rio.
Happy Birthday Kid.
Glad you turned 18.
Beat it!
-Just a beer!
-Didn't you see me asshole?
Next time, I will kill
you prick!
Kid was ready for everything!
And couldn't wait.
Who is the wealthiest here?
Easy!
Jerry Andriani...
Gold necklace, luxurious clothes.
-Perriera and the chick.
-My brother took her.
Look at the ride.
Here is Blackie.
Covered with gold.
Redhead. Nice wheels!
All of the dealers.
-All of them wealthy.
-Robberies are shit.
The big money
is in dealing drugs.
-Especially coke.
-Needs capital though.
We will kill them
and take it over.
-When do we start?
-Now.
The light of Satan
brought you here!
Why do you live in the City of God
that God has forgotten?
I know what you want.
You want power.
I have something that will give
you the power you're looking for.
This will change your fate.
I give you my amulet.
Just do not fuck
while you wear it...
because you will die!
The kid will no longer be Kid
but Ze.
Little Ze grew up.
If you help me,
I will help you.
This way, Kid became Ze
and started the killings.
One morning
he took over Andriani's gang...
until one night, he ruled
all the ghetto gangs.
He did not harm Redhead
since he was Bennie's friend.
Only the hideout was left.
But it was an easy job.
Who is it?
Fuck off Kid. Why are you
rushing into my hideout?
Since when is it your hideout?
Anything wrong Kid?
I am not Kid.
My name is Ze!
-You're dead bastard.
-No, he understands.
It's all yours. I want nothing.
I do not want trouble.
I had to take vegeance
on my brother's death.
You are gonna live,
but you will work for us.
Easy to say.
-Where are you going?
-He's clean Ze.
-What is your name?
-Rocket
Naive's brother.
Dead Naive's brother.
Go and tell everyone
that Ze is now in charge.
We are selling coke.
Got it?
Drug dealing is a job too!
The supplier brings the merchantise
which is packed.
It is all a chain.
Pot is wrapped.
Coke is packed in 10s or 100s.
You can be a
carrier or a drug dealer.
The kids start as messengers.
Then they do lookouts.
If the cops come,
they all vanish.
Then you become a dealer.
In hard times,
the dealer vanishes.
Growing up,
you become captain.
And if you are good in
math, you become a manager.
Bosses right hand.
The cops get their cut
and stay out of it.
Whan Ze came,
all the rivalries stopped in the City.
You could go there.
Bohemian people bought
their dope safely.
Lots of people became addicts
and Ze became rich.
-Which one should I wear?
-This is cool.
If drug dealing was legal
Ze would be given an Oscar.
I thought that they all
were very dangerous.
However he was everywhere.
If I needed pot,
I had to visit Redhead.
-Half a pound.
-Thanks.
It was worth it.
I smoked it with Angelica.
She had broken up with Siago
and so I made my move.
Fantastic photos.
Do I look good here?
You look good in all of them.
Twilight, an empty beach,
a long-lasting kiss..
That was it...
But the Shorties came...
Will you give me a drag?
Here.
See you later.
-Your joint!
-Keep it!
First time I met
the Shorties.
Steak and potatoes.
-This is for you.
-All of it? Thanks.
Do you want to have something to eat?
Can you change the time in the clock please?
After he broke up, Siago
sniffed more and more everyday.
When you become an addict,
you're in the dealer's hands.
-Two bags of ten.
-One bag.
For Siago it was not like that.
-Sorry, godfather.
-Bullshit, did I baptize you?
Give me your bike,
Blackie.
Do you wanna race?
Till the bus.
Ready? Go!
-Hard race.
-You're good.
-Where did you buy the trainers from?
-From the neighbourhood.
-And the shirt?
-From the City.
It is an expensive brand.
If I give you the money
will you buy me one?
Shorts and shirt?
Buy whatever you can.
-What is your size?
-Measure me!
-With what?
-With you!
Shoe number?
Turn around.
-Benny!
-Did you get the goodies?
-Just a pair of trousers?
-There is more.
Do you like it?
-You have some change.
-Keep it.
This is Benny.
I became bohemian.
Gangsters, listen.
Beware...
Groovies are making moves
before the big boom.
Fuck you, bastards!
Prick!
Redhead is placing
the ghetto in danger.
Go talk to him. You can't
just shoot everybody.
Don't worry,
the lads here are ok.
I don't worry!
Will you dance, Benny? What
happened with the Redhead?
Go talk to him!
Benny was the coolest
gangster in the City.
He gave away dope,
paid for his drinks.
Ze was the opposite.
He was obsessed.
Wanted to become the big ghetto boss.
He was looking for the opportunity
to take over Redhead's gang.
Don't let the Shorties
rob the whole ghetto.
You mind your business
and I will mind mine.
I'm going for a drink.
How is it going Rocket?
Siago, what's up?
Want to dance?
Can we go to your place?
My parents are not home.
You're gonna be alone.
Today you can
lose your virginity!
Don't shout!
Everyone will hear!
You're pretty.
It's ok.
I know you are related to
the Shorties.
Do you think I am stupid?
You want my gang?
I just want to talk to you.
You are useless!
The Shorties
are endagering us.
Ask them to cool down.
He lets them plunder
in his ghetto, he's useless.
If police come here
we're fucked.
I will do it because I like you.
Change his diapers!
Tell him that no one
plunders in my ghetto!
Shorties do not respect
the ghetto rules.
They steal from ordinary people
and rob bakeries.
You're stealing from me all the time!
However, they didn't know
the city had a new boss!
THANK YOU
FOR PREFERING US
The city has become safer
for the inhabitants.
Robberies are rare.
All you have to do is visit Ze.
-Do not touch Shorties
-I don't.
-Let's go for a walk
-Together?
Mom, I am going out
with my friends.
I have never tasted a better chicken!
-The old man was scared to death!
-You feel sorry for him?
Should we rob a bank
or a supermarket?
Bullshit. All the money
is in drug dealing.
You have to start as
a messenger.
It is no good. Takes too
much time to be promoted.
You have to wait for
an old guy to get killed.
I won't wait for anyone to
bite the dust. I'll do as Ze.
Are you talknig about be kid?
The boss is here.
Come back, you tramp!
They run fast!
Anyone else?
You're gonna pay for
the ones who run away.
Shall I shoot you
in the arm or the leg?
-Choose.
-Hand or leg?
Choose, dammit!
-In the hand.
-In the hand, eh?
Let's see about you.
Kill one of them.
-I'll do it!
-Beat it! He's gonna do it.
Pick whom you'll kill.
-We don't have all day.
-Kill one of them.
Get it over with, Steak.
I want to see if you have the guts.
Well done! You did it!
You're one of us. Gimme five.
Get up, tramp.
Go back to your shithole.
Stop limping!
Tell your friends
no one steals from Ze.
www.subtitlesworld.com