While Ze was earning the
respect of the locals..
Benny was winning
Angelica's heart.
I was still a virgin and broke
I had no other choice.
THE LIFE OF A SUCKER
I found a job
in a supermarket.
I was working for just a few nickels.
I wanted to be fired..
to buy a camera
with my wages.
But my fate
was different.
The guy from the beach!
Do you still smoke?
Kid!
Pull your shirt.
Is this a thank you?
-My compensation?
-Which compensation?
The fucking manager
thought I participated.
You are fired
because of violation of duty. Beat it!
I did not get a dime.
A message from God.
''Honesty is
punished, sucker.''
FLIRTING WITH CRIME
The bus is late.
I should have been at work.
-Hide the gun! Are you mad?
-It's broken.
-It is not our fault.
-It is never anyone's fault!
But we pay the price.
Goodnight, lady.
I know him. He lives
in the City. He will recognize us.
It is his boss's
money. He doesn't care!
Aren't you
From the City of God?
Only one shall pay.
Study, only this way
you can leave the ghetto.
-Do you study?
-I attended school and then I joined the army.
I was a good shot.
Then, I found this job.
I have knowledge of karate. If I find a job
elsewhere I will leave the ghetto.
Do you fight?
I am peaceful.
But if I have to..
And he was going to have to. But I
will talk about Knockout later.
We are leaving. Bye.
-I couldn't, he was cool.
-He is Gerson's brother.
Let's go home.
There is only a bakery here.
-What are you going to say?
-I don't know! ''Robbery!''
-My phone.
-Prefer soul or groovie?
Nothing again. The girl
was very sexy. She flirted with me.
I couldn't pull the gun,
she was so sweet.
I am lost. How do
I get to Bara?
"The guy from Sao Paolo
was unlucky", I thought.
That's where we are going too.
You are saving me.
Everybody from
Sao Paolo is a nasty piece of work.
We found the body, officer!
Not a pretty sight eh?
Awesome singer.
I like music. Do you?
You like pot too?
Never tried.
I thought so.
-Do you have paper?
-I have some.
I was a professor in rolling joints.
If only I was like that
with girls!
I would not be a virgin still.
For a guy from Sao Paolo
you're cool.
What did they kill her with?
With a bat or a rock.
-The kid.
-They did not hurt it.
-How long ago?
-About four hours.
Shall we take it?
The murderer must
be from the City of God.
Motherfucker!
You should have killed her in the
ghetto! Cops are coming!
It was a mater of honour.
Her parents gave me away.
The place is full of cops
because of you! Asshole!
You punished him enough, Ze.
Whoever kills in my
ghetto, dies.
He had issues, Ze.
Leave the ghetto.
You showed disrespect!
The snake will bite you,
Benny.
-He was useless.
-A dirty traitor.
I am going for a walk with the girl.
Take care. When
things calm down...
we will deal with
Redhead again.
Get a girlfriend, Ze.
-Do you know what I am thinking?
-That I am sexy?
That too. Do you know
what we can do?
-Make love?
-I am serious.
Get out of here.
I hate violence.
-And go where?
-To a farm.
We are hippies at heart.
To a farm?
Peace and love?
BENNY'S FAREWELL
Benny was too cool
to be a gangster.
With his party, he managed
to bring everyone together.
Gangs...
Soul fans...
Religious people...
Some day, I'll go to the church.
Samba fans...
Groovies...
And Ze
who danced for the first time in his life.
Wanna dance?
-I can't hear you.
-Are you dancing?
Thanks, I got company.
I want to talk to you.
You are no going away
with that chick.
I'll live in a farm,
I'll smoke pot, and listen to rock.
Are you going to ruin everything
for a bitch?
She's my girl.
I will kill
Redhead, the bastard.
You think that everybody is a bastard
that is why I'm leaving!
I am your friend but I am leaving.
Try to understand.
I love you but that's all.
Show me your balls man!
You wanna die? Beat it!
Pull your pants down nigger!
I wanna see your ass!
Come on you faggot!
Show us your ass!
Put them down!
The camera
for a bag of coke?
-No more shit.
-You're my friend.
-Is it stolen?
-My father's.
-Give it to Ze.
-Rocket will probably want it.
Here I am!
You want to be a photographer?
Here's a present.
Awesome!
Shake your ass!
You're gonna shoot
fine photos.
Bring it here.
-Give me the camera!
-No.
They killed Benny!
Call an ambulance!
Who the fuck did it?
Ze, Benny is dead.
It's your fault bitch!
-Where is Redhead?
-Blackie's here.
We're fucked.
-Why?
-We're both fucked.
I think I killed
Benny.
Ze is coming. We can
catch up with him in the disco.
-Did you kill Benny?
-Accidentally. I aimed at Ze.
Blackie, you killed the coolest
gangster in the City.
Without Benny, Redhead
was dead.
We're fucked, man.
Where else could a miracle happen
if not in the City of God?
Hello doll.
Gimme a kiss.
Let me pass.
Have you ever seen your face?
All's well baby?
It was simple as that.
Ze was ugly.
Knockout Ned
was handsome.
Knockout had whomever he wanted.
Ze had to use violence.
A duel between the good
and charming...
and the bad and ugly.
Let go me!
Enjoy it.
No need to resist.
You are mine now.
Your girlfriend
is hot. Lucky bastard.
I cannot even look at her.
Why didn't the motherfucker
kill me?
Why didn't I kill
the asshole?
-Let's go back.
-And Redhead?
-We'll be back.
-Are you going to kill him?
Knockout, Come out.
Take it easy.
I am going out. Let go me.
Garson, come back!
None of your business kid.
It is your brother we want!
My brother is peaceful!
Is he too pretty
to talk to me? Tell him to come out!
He did nothing.
Do you know who I am?
I'm Ze!
Bring the motherfucker!
Cool down, I'll bring him.
I'm hit. Redhead will be
waiting. He asked for it.
The bastard
killed my brother!
I won't let it go.
Need a gun?
-My child!
-Take it easy mom.
-Do it right.
-There is no other way.
-How could he hit me?
-That's a bad hole.
We were like brothers.
You were hit by one brother
me by the other!
Knockout isn't bad.
He came out of nowhere.
You give me a headache, Tuba!
The City of God
found its hero.
God bless you.
The kid went looking for trouble.
You did a fine job.
You have to hide.
I though Knockout would start
a revolution here.
But God had
other plans.
Steak, where did the
dealers disappear?
They are hiding.
Ze is not in a good mood.
They put us in it
and then they hide.
-Bring me a chocolate.
-I'll try.
Tell her that
Siago is looking for her.
Steak, go tell Redhead. . .
that Ze says if you kill Knockout
he'll leave you alone.
-Did you hear this Knockout?
-Get the kid!
If you don't stay with us,
you're dead.
Come with us.
We'll be partners.
I do not like drugs.
It's between me and him.
They are scum. They'd do
anything for power.
Like the Kid here
They are all like robots.
Do you have shit inside your head?
Don't you understand that you are
wasted with this maniac?
You are kiddo!
Kid, huh? I sniff. I steal.
I kill. I am man!
He is stuck to his gang. Come with us
We will slice you, Steak.
Ok, I accept.
Tell him that Redhead and Knockout
are in charge.
With one condition:
I don't kill innocents.
-I won't tolerate it.
-Ok, no innocents.
Steak is fucked up.
-Have you got a gun?
-We'll rob a gun store.
I don't rob anything.
I am not a gangster.
I have something personal with him
I am not a robber.
He raped your girl,
he killed your brother. . .
he hit your house and you
killed a acolyte of his.
Unless you are a robber,
get out.
KNOCKOUT NED'S HISTORY
Robbery !
The first time...
Bring the revolvers!
...Knockout Ned saved
a dealer from Redhead.
We said no killings.
It's a rule!
We want the boss' money! Open the register!
Do you want to leave? We also want it.
The second time, Redhead
saved Knockout
Ned learned that rules
have exceptions.
An exception .
Are you the director?
Robbery! Everybody down!
I don't play. Whoever moves
will be shot!
The third time,
the exception became a rule.
With the money from the robberies,
they would face Ze.
Redhead would protect his business.
Knockout, the best
shooter, wanted revenge.
The Italian first.
This is 9mm.
-It's not aligned.
-You'll get it at a good price.
This is a 12mm.
We call it ''crap''.
Uzi,9mm. From Israel.
David's star.
I want a 30-06.
It's party time!
The war begins.
Lets pray.
Our Father,
who art in heaven...
hallowed be thy name...
Gangsters have the guns
but they don't shoot.
Knockout's one bullet
was like ten of Ze's bullets.
Ze couldn't stand it.
He attacked.
The ghetto was like Hell
but now it had become Hell!
I decided to get out.
That's how I became a journalist.
Nice picture!
That's Rogerio Ris' for sure.
What was I saying?
As every professional. . .
I started at the lowest level,
from the bottom.
Without knowing
what was ahead of me...
Instead if going home,
I went to the newspaper's offices.
Someone from the City of God
worked at the laboratory.
He helped me to fulfill
the dream of my life .
Rogerio, this is
Rocket. A photographer.
-He is an admirer of yours.
-You have a good taste, Rocket.
I am leaving.
Nice guy!
A personal revenge
lead to war.
The City of God has been divided.
You couldn't
cross it.
Nor to go to a relative.
Those who lived to the ghetto
were considered gangsters.
We were living our own Vietnam. .
Volunteers
were giving their lives.
The Kids.
Somebody hit me.
The war
was changing everything.
One of Ze's guys kicked me.
Take this.
He raped my sister...
-Ze took our home.
-Kill for your pride.
I am Siago,
Benny's friend.
You know how to read?
Spell?
-I am good.
-You are hired.
To revenge my father's
killer.
-What's your name?
-My name is Oto.
What's happening?
-He works.
-He needs a gun.
He won't last a week.
A year later, nobody
remembered how it all started.
The aim was, to undertake
enemy's business...
to buy guns and to extend
the enterprise.
I sniff, I killed, I stole.
I am man!
The TV showed interest.
The police would intervene.
A gangster from
the city of God, was arrested.
Manuel Massando
also known as Knockout Ned...
is at hospital after an attack
of Ze's gang.
He gave us an interview.
-Does the war continue?
-Yes, it continues.
Were many people killed?
Many. Innocent mostly.
If a person knows me
that's enough for Ze to kill him.
-Are the police absent?
-They hunt me, not him.
I am in jail while he
kills people without bothering.
Knockout Ned believes
that the war will continue.
Cops promised
to dislocate the gangs.
I am the boss and he is
in the newspaper!
-Did you find mine?
-Knockout's only.
My name must be somewhere.
-Can you read?
-The pictures. Nothing.
-What the Hell are you doing?
-Those are the announcements.
Read everything!
-There are no articles!
-Do you want to be shot?
We'll show them
who is the boss!
Give me the camera!
-Take a picture .
-I don't know how it works.
Take me.
Back...
-It doesn't click.
-You fools.
You fucked me, assholes.
I'll call an acquaintance.
He came.
Take the camera.
Well, Kid?
Aren't you a photographer?
Take a picture.
-You broke it.
-Not me.
Needs some fixing.
-What's your name?
-Rocket.
Pull one more.
Two lines.
With your guns.
-You're out, Dammit!
-Speak kindly.
-Show us the pictures.
-We must develop these photos.
How much does it cost?
Take this money
and bring the pictures.
-I have to remove the film.
-No, No. Take the camera.
Benny wanted to give it to you.
It is yours.
Don't forget
the pictures.
Can you develop
this film?
I can't, Rocket,
I'll get in trouble.
I work only for the newspaper. I'll get fired.
Develop this, Pierre.
And this.
I am going for lunch.
You are lucky.
Dimensions?
For the enlargement.
Whatever you think is best.
I am in big trouble.
I am dead.
Somebody signed
my death sentence.
I would smash his face!
You stole my pictures!
They will kill me!
What are you talking about?
They'll kill me
because of you!
The pictures
were at the laboratory.
Everything that is in the laboratory
is for publication.
-I saw them, I published them.
-You stole them.
-Give them to me.
-Here, take them.
-Don't you have more?
-Relax. What's your name?
Rocket?
Nice to meet you, Marina.
Relax. I've got your money.
When a picture is published
we pay the photographer.
Do you want to become a photographer?
Nice start with a front page!
-How did you take them?
-I live there.
Not even one photographer managed
to go to the ghetto.
If you bring more
pictures of Ze. . .
the newspaper will buy them.
-Can you?
-I don't know.
-What's the problem?
-I can't go there again at night.
-And the day?
-It is a risk.
At last they understand
that I'm the Boss.
What's the name of this photographer
friend of yours?
He is good. I'll take some
to show.
Yes, or not?
It's a big chance.
You made the right decision.
I'll give you film, lenses
and another camera.
Come to see the equipment
office.
There is another problem also.
Where am I going to sleep tonight?
I can't go back.
This one is a 135 mm.
Do you shoot from near or from a distance?
-Can you measure the light?
-Yes.
Don't you think you are too close?
I don't know how I managed
to talk to them like this.
Maybe I was about to die
but I had a camera. . .
and a chance
to become a photographer.
What is more, we had
the whole night for us.
-Do you want to eat something?
-No thanks.
Won't you eat, or drink?
A joint?
Try this.
Time to sleep.
-I'll show you your bed
-Have you got hot water?
Yes, haven't you tried a
hot bath?
No. We get boiling water
from the saucepan.
-Why are you standing there?
-In which room am I going to sleep?
Unfortunately, I have only one room.
We will sleep together.
I won't tell you much
about my first sexual experience.
Somewhere else, another one, a more important
erotic scene was taking place.
Redhead was helping Knockout
to escape.
without a shot.
The guard was in
the hands of the nurse.
Meanwhile, Ze
was investing on ammo...
To terminate
Redhead.
He was heavily equipped even though
he didn't have the money to pay.
Did you remember the shotgun?
It is a semi automatic shotgun.
You haven't seen a Browning like this.
It can even shoot down airplanes.
I want what I asked for.
The American AR-15.
-They don't exist in Brazil.
-I don't give a shit.
I've got the solution. Ruger
Have you seen this before?
Like the AR-15. Same calibre
but lighter.
With infrared vision ?
400 blasts per minute?
Are you trying to fool me?
I'll fuck you.
Go now. No money.
No guns.
What am I supposed to say to the boss?
-Your problem. Think of something.
Beat it, Fatty
Ze made a big mistake
he didn't know that...
Behind every dealer
there is a big trader.
Did you see this?
Why do they want an AR-15?
They will make investigations
cops. We'll get busted.
Do you think that I will betray you?
I'll fix it, but
don't get involved again.
Charlie! Come here.
Tell him...
Let's go now to the fucking dealer.
Come here, kids.
-Do you like chicken?
-It depends.
We'll eat chicken and
for dessert...Redhead.
I have a gift for you.
-One big for you.
-Are you giving us guns?
Yes, but I want you with me
against Redhead.
-Can we steal later?
-Not in the ghetto.
-Do you know how to shoot?
-More or less.
Come to help
the kids!
I know. You do it like this.
THE BEGINING OF THE END
Grab the chicken!
If Ze catches you,
he'll kill you.
He has to find me first.
Kid, grab the chicken!
-The Cops!
-Don't run away!
Butthead! Fuckin' faggot!
Get the Hell outta here!
Let them kill
each other
Rocket!
Take our picture!
Why are you standing there?
Kill the motherfucker!
-Relax, don't move.
-It hurts!
Relax, kid!
Why did you join
this fuckin' war?
Knockout Ned!
Ze is down!
Hang on, I'll help you.
-What's your name
-My name is Otto.
I want revenge
for my father's death.
Ze's down!
Hang on.
Cops!
Down! Hands behind your head!
-It's you that I want.
-You're through, pal.
Handcuff him.
-Rocket, where are you going?
-I got something to do.
We got some arrangements to do, Ze.
Not you. You're the gift
for the Media.
-Is it 10,000?
-Almost. That's all I got.
That's all, Boss.
We looked everywhere.
Let him go.
The ring? Is it gold?
Fuck it.
You owe us the rest.
Fuckin' war!
Knockout Ned is dead
and I'm broke!
Your fucked, right?
We'll do some robberies
to get back my job.
-Your job, Ze?
-Is it tough for you, boy?
For our friend, motherfucker!
Attack!
We are the Bosses!
That photograph
will make me a professional.
That photograph, will make me famous.
Maybe it becomes a frond page
of a magazine.
I won't worry about Ze anymore.
But the police?
The Boss of the City
of God, falls down dead...
That photograph...
It could kill us.
-It gave you work .
-It made me internal.
-You make some money, right?
-Yeah, some...
-That journalist? Was she good?
-Good enough.
-You didn't like it?
-How would they know about fucking?
Cocoa stole three houses
at Bara.
Let's do him.
-Who killed Roger?
-Bif.
Let's kill the Boss
and Gringo.
It's just the two of us
plus three more...
Have you ever heard
of the Red Brigade?
No, but if they come
we'll do 'em.
-Who knows how to write?
-Me, a little.
Let's make
a Black List.
Add in the List: Nightbird
and Leonard!
And the Chinese, he thinks too
important. Claudio also!
Where is Giant?
I forgot to tell you,
my name is not Rocket any more.
I'm Wilson Rodriguez.
Photographer.
Based on a true story
Manuel Assando also known as
Knockout Ned, was hospitalized...
after he was "injured"
by Ze's men.
He gave us an interview.
Many died.
Mostly innocent.
just for knowing me. . .
just for being my friends.
If someone thinks that
he knows me, he's dead.
-Where is the police?
-They're after me, not him.
I went three times to jail while
he kills undisturbed.
They don't arrest him.
Knockout Ned claims
that the war will be continued.
Police officers promised
to take down...
both gangs
in the City of God.
www.subtitlesworld.com